Register to The Leo Ornstein Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Music, Series I
  - Orchestral Music, I.D
    - Five Songs for voice & orchestra (Texts by Waldo Frank) (Box 8)
      Song II: Holograph score in ink, with pencil text [Parts same as for song I] -- 21 p.
      Song III: Holograph score in ink, with pencil text [Parts same as for song I] -- 25 p.
      Song IV: Holograph score in ink, with pencil text [Parts same as for song I] -- 30 p.
      Song V: Holograph score in ink, with pencil text [Parts same as for song I] -- 18 p.
    - Piano concerto, 99 p. (Box 9)
      Holograph score in ink and pencil
      one reel of microfilm
    - Piano concerto, 110 p. (Box 9)
      Holograph score in ink of 2-piano version
      Photocopy of 2-piano version
      [N.B. the photocopy of the 2-piano version contains changes made by Ornstein for the revival performance in Dec. 1976. These changes are in the hand of William Westney]
    - Piano concerto (Box 10–11, Box 11A–11B)
      Holograph set of parts
      Photocopy set of parts for performance
    - Piano concerto Incidental music for the play of Lysistrata (Box 12)
      Negative photostat copy of the score
      Holograph score of section called "Lament of Young Men"
    - Piano concerto Incidental music for the play of Lysistrata (Box 13)
      Photocopy of holograph of section "Bacchanale" (1930?)
      One reel microfilm
      Holograph and negative photostat of instrumental parts (49 p.)
      Copies of piano, violin, viola, cello, bass, flute, clarinet, trumpet, trombone and percussion parts [2 sets]
    - Lysistrata Suite, for orchestra (Box 14)
      Holograph score of Prelude to Act I, Burlesque & Funeral march, Prelude to Act II, and opening Fanfare (for trumpet and trombone)
      Photocopy of holograph score in its entirety: Prelude to Act I, Burlesque & Funeral March, Prelude to Act II, Bacchanale -- 119 p.
      Holograph set of string parts for entire piece, made separately from the set of parts.
    - Lysistrata Suite, for orchestra (Box 15)
      Complete set of parts
      Violin I - 1 holograph and 10 copies
      Violin II - 1 holograph and 10 copies
      Viola - I holograph and 8 copies
      Cello - 1 holograph and 8 copies
      Bass - 1 holograph and 8 copies
      Flutes I, II, III - holographs
      Oboes I, II, III - holographs
      English Horn - holograph for Burlesque, Prelude II and Bacchanale only
      Clarinet I, II, III - holograph
      Bass Clarinet - holograph
      Bassoon I, II, III - holograph
      Contrabassoon - holograph
      Horn I, II, III - holograph
      Trumpet I, II, III,IV - holograph
      Trombone I, II, III - holograph
      Tuba - holograph
      Timpani - holograph
      Percussion - 1 holograph and 4 copies
      Large drum - holograph
    - Lysistrata Suite, for orchestra (Box 16–17)
      Copyflow set of parts to Lysistrata Suite, arranged by separate movements
      Prelude to Act I
      Burlesque and Funeral March
      Prelude to Act II
      Bacchanale
- Photographs, Series II
  The photographs in this collection were donated by several persons, including Ornstein's niece and Mrs. Vivian Perlis. They are arranged in approximate chronological order, and include pictures of Leo Ornstein as a child, as a concert pianist and as a composer in later life.
  - Ornstein in Russia, ca. 1904; 1 item (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - ca. 1908, 1 item (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - ca. 1910, 1 item (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - ca. 1910, 1 item (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Program, 1914; 1 item (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Postcard, portrait, ca. 1915; 1 item (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - With brother, Aaron, ca. 1916; 1 item (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - ca. 1918, 1 item (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - ca. 1918, 1 item (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Program, 1937; 1 item (Box 18, Folder 1)
    (photo ca. 1918)
  - ca. 1940, 1 item (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - ca. 1945, 1 item (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 31 items (Box 18, Folder 1)
    Pictures, publicity photos, etc... and a photo button contained in a separate individual envelope
- Miscellaneous, Series III
  - Biographical clippings, 15 items (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Incomplete works in Yale's collection with annotations by Mrs. Ornstein, 8 items (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - First draft of list of complete Ornstein manuscripts with annotations by Mrs. Ornstein, 13 items (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Tape of Tartar Dance, performed by Andrew Imbrie, and tape donated to collection by him (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Frederick Martens Leo Ornstein - The man, his ideas, his work (Box 18, Folder 4)
    Photocopy of book
  - Press accounts and reviews of concert performances given by and of Ornstein's works, 20 items (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Concert programs both of Ornstein performances and performances of his music, 16 items (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence both to and from the Ornsteins, 12 items (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Material related to Ornstein as a pedagogue, 8 items (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous prose writings of Pauline Ornstein, 7 items (Box 19, Folder 5)
    Short essay of Leo's aesthetic (4 p.)
    Reminiscences from here, there & everywhere (49 p.)
    Shortcuts in taking dictation (2 p.)
    Reminiscences continued (17 unnumbered pages) [see letter of 12 March 1975]
    What is music? (120 p.)
    Notes and copy of analysis of Ornstein Quintet on Hotel Sylvania (Philadelphia) stationary and addressed to a Miss Lederman
  - Brooklyn Museum booklet on William Zorach exhibit containing HIS Leo Ornstein Piano Concert, 1918 on p. 46. (Box 19, Folder 5)